<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Patents on ig.nore.me </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/patents/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Zealand Parliament adopts UK approach to software patents, allows broad swaths of them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/new-zealand-parliament-adopts-uk-approach-to-software-patents-allows-broad-swaths-of-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/new-zealand-parliament-adopts-uk-approach-to-software-patents-allows-broad-swaths-of-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At best, one can read between the lines of that bill that there was some pressure to be restrictive in connection with software patents&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I might have been celebrating too early with my link yesterday. According to this article there is far too much wriggle room left, so that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to get software patented after all. Unfortunately, for some strange reason laws are written in a way that you need to be an expert to understand them; and I&amp;rsquo;m not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which means I can&amp;rsquo;t say for certain if this article is correct, but it seems likely. Now, if only the NSA hadn&amp;rsquo;t caused Groklaw to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.groklaw.net/article.php?story=20130818120421175&#34;&gt;shut down&lt;/a&gt; it might have been dissected and explained there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Zealand bans software patents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/new-zealand-bans-software-patents/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 08:35:15 EST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/new-zealand-bans-software-patents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patents system doesn’t work for software because it is almost impossible for genuine technology companies to create new software without breaching some of the hundreds of thousands of software patents that exist, often for very obvious work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart decision in New Zealand, making the country an even more awesome place!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>